<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FLCA</title>
    <link>https://flca.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on FLCA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://flca.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes on 64, NO on 67: Pot and Personhood in Colorado</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/yeson64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/yeson64/</guid>
      <description>You made history voting Yes on 64 in 2012. Here’s why you should vote No on 67 in 2014.
Colorado voters made headlines at the polls two years ago when the passage of ballot initiative Amendment 64 made recreational marijuana legal for adults over the age of 21. The vote heralded a new era in cannabis law reform, and was an important step towards rectifying the profound damage created by marijuana prohibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/board/</guid>
      <description>Sara Arnold aka Sahra Kant
Sara Arnold aka Sahra Kant is a hard-working drug policy advocate and activist committed to ending the persecution of pregnant women and parents (of all genders) for cannabis use in criminal or civil matters. She is one of two people in Massachusetts and one of very few reformers who speaks on this issue throughout the United States. A dual-citizen born and raised in Massachusetts, she has been increasingly and extensively active in the drug policy movement since her teens on local, national and international levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Resources</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/legal-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/legal-resources/</guid>
      <description>Request for non-legal advice and legal referrals We cannot help everyone who contacts us or assist with every case. Non-legal advice and legal referrals is operated on a volunteer basis and we receive many more requests than we can feasibly help with in our time constraints. We do not always have advice or referrals for every state beyond what exists on this website. We will provide non-legal advice and legal referrals wherever possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/links/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources Backline
Childproofing Your House For Maximum Medical Marijuana Anti-Diversion and Safety (PDF)
FightCPS.com
Mothers Against Misuse and Abuse (MAMA)
Other Organizations Americans for Civil Liberties (ACLU)
Americans for Safe Access (ASA)
Children of Prohibition
Drug Policy Alliance (DPA)
Efficacy
Forward Together: Strong Families
Green Aid: Medical Marijuana Legal Defense &amp;amp; Education Fund
The Human Solution
International Association for Cannabinoid Medicines
Law Enforcement Against Prohibition (LEAP)
Marijuana Majority</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/media/</guid>
      <description>Around the Web  Mentions, quotes, interviews, and published work from FLCA and its founders.
 FLCA in the Media
August 20, 2015: Newsweek, “Women in Weed: How Legal Marijuana Could Be the First Billion-Dollar Industry Not Dominated by Men” by Gogo Lidz
July 28, 2015: The Fix, “How Medical Marijuana Users Are Treated Like Criminals” by Keri Blakinger
July 4, 2015: Marijuana Politics, “Marijuana Consumers Becoming Legal, But Not Yet Free” by Russ Belville</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need Help?</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/help/</guid>
      <description>Request for a speaker from FLCA to come talk to your conference, convention, rally, festival, school, or other event Our founders, Sara Arnold aka Sahra Kant and Jess Cochrane, are available individually or together for speaking engagement at your event by ourselves, in a workshop, on a panel, or any other format. We appreciate as much notice as possible to ensure that we are able to attend your event. Due to the cost of local or national travel and our organization being operated on a volunteer basis, please let us know if you are able to reimburse the cost of transport, lodging, or any other expenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent-Protective Model Language</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/policy/</guid>
      <description>We offer this best-practice, gold standard model language for parent-protective provisions in progressive marijuana legislation and ballot initiatives. Current parent-protective provisions in state-level cannabis laws are do not provide the level of protection families deserve. Each word in FLCA’s model language has been chosen deliberately and carefully to fully protect parents from experiencing assessments, investigations, actions and proceedings by CPS or in family or juvenile court regarding child welfare or custodial matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Bars: Drug War Ideology in the Civil Child Welfare System</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/beyondbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/beyondbars/</guid>
      <description>Among drug policy reform activists, there is a consensus that punitive approaches should not constitute the bulk of our national strategy to reduce the harms associated with addiction and problematic use of drugs. Whether in recognition of its fiscal irresponsibility, its conflict with public health goals, or its disparate impact on brown, black , and poor communities, we agree that mass incarceration is not an appropriate solution to the problems caused b y drugs themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shocking State of Cannabis-Related Child Protection in Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/protection/</guid>
      <description>Picture this. You’re celebrating your state having legalized marijuana; perhaps you’re in Massachusetts circa 2016. Medical cannabis was legalized years earlier and decriminalization years before that. “The war on cannabis is over”, you think to yourself as you straighten your party hat and inhale deeply on your Kush, “we’ve won.”
Then you get a call from the Department of Children &amp;amp; Families (DCF), Massachusetts’ child protection services, that you’ve been reported to them anonymously for marijuana use and you’re going to be immediately investigated for neglect of your child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocky Mountain Risk</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/risk/</guid>
      <description>Modified version published by Ladybud Magazine as “How Will Colorado’s Marijuana Legalization Laws Effect Families?” on January 7, 2014.
In May, Colorado Governor John Hickenlooper signed into law historic legislation regulating the growth, sale, and use of the marijuana in the Rocky Mountain state, and several related bills have been signed or are expected to be signed. In many ways they are excellent documents and should be celebrated as very much in line with the Colorado voters who passed their cannabis legalization law by a 55% margin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Protective Services &amp; Family Court: The Last Gasp of the War on Cannabis</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/familycourt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/familycourt/</guid>
      <description>Original version published in Mass Grass as “The National Picture.” This version published by Ladybud Magazine as “Child Protective Services &amp;amp; Family Court: The Last Gasp of the Drug War” on November 5, 2013.
What’s worse than going to jail for cannabis? Your children taken away by child protection services for it. If you’re incarcerated, you receive a specific custodial sentence — which may be reduced for good behavior or perhaps even commuted — during which you are guaranteed visits with your family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandated Reporting of Substance-Exposed Newbornsin an Era of Changing Marijuana Laws</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/reporting/</guid>
      <description>i n partial fulfillment of the requirements of the Master’s in Public Health degree Tufts University School of Medicine Adviser: Marcia Boumil 2 Abstract This qualitative analysis examines the intersection of two separate sets of policy :
Mandated reporting of child abuse &amp;amp; neglect, and the state level regulation of marijuana, or cannabis. Through policies and laws created to address the needs of infants who are born
exposed to controlled substances, substance exposed newborn (SEN) initiatives provide the focal point at which these two regimes come together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marijuana and Child Custody</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/custody/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/custody/</guid>
      <description>Originally published in Mass Grass.
One of the most common types of cases heard in family court — and one of the most bitterly fought — is child custody. Spend a single day in one court room at any courthouse in Massachusetts or elsewhere in the country and you’ll hear a whole host of allegations made by parents or their legal representatives about each other. Often these accusations have to do with cannabis for medicinal or recreational use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/blog/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/blog/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>