<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on FLCA</title>
    <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on FLCA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://flca.netlify.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes on 64, NO on 67: Pot and Personhood in Colorado</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/yeson64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/yeson64/</guid>
      <description>You made history voting Yes on 64 in 2012. Here’s why you should vote No on 67 in 2014.
Colorado voters made headlines at the polls two years ago when the passage of ballot initiative Amendment 64 made recreational marijuana legal for adults over the age of 21. The vote heralded a new era in cannabis law reform, and was an important step towards rectifying the profound damage created by marijuana prohibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Bars: Drug War Ideology in the Civil Child Welfare System</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/beyondbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/beyondbars/</guid>
      <description>Among drug policy reform activists, there is a consensus that punitive approaches should not constitute the bulk of our national strategy to reduce the harms associated with addiction and problematic use of drugs. Whether in recognition of its fiscal irresponsibility, its conflict with public health goals, or its disparate impact on brown, black , and poor communities, we agree that mass incarceration is not an appropriate solution to the problems caused b y drugs themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shocking State of Cannabis-Related Child Protection in Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/protection/</guid>
      <description>Picture this. You’re celebrating your state having legalized marijuana; perhaps you’re in Massachusetts circa 2016. Medical cannabis was legalized years earlier and decriminalization years before that. “The war on cannabis is over”, you think to yourself as you straighten your party hat and inhale deeply on your Kush, “we’ve won.”
Then you get a call from the Department of Children &amp;amp; Families (DCF), Massachusetts’ child protection services, that you’ve been reported to them anonymously for marijuana use and you’re going to be immediately investigated for neglect of your child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocky Mountain Risk</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/risk/</guid>
      <description>Modified version published by Ladybud Magazine as “How Will Colorado’s Marijuana Legalization Laws Effect Families?” on January 7, 2014.
In May, Colorado Governor John Hickenlooper signed into law historic legislation regulating the growth, sale, and use of the marijuana in the Rocky Mountain state, and several related bills have been signed or are expected to be signed. In many ways they are excellent documents and should be celebrated as very much in line with the Colorado voters who passed their cannabis legalization law by a 55% margin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Protective Services &amp; Family Court: The Last Gasp of the War on Cannabis</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/familycourt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/familycourt/</guid>
      <description>Original version published in Mass Grass as “The National Picture.” This version published by Ladybud Magazine as “Child Protective Services &amp;amp; Family Court: The Last Gasp of the Drug War” on November 5, 2013.
What’s worse than going to jail for cannabis? Your children taken away by child protection services for it. If you’re incarcerated, you receive a specific custodial sentence — which may be reduced for good behavior or perhaps even commuted — during which you are guaranteed visits with your family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandated Reporting of Substance-Exposed Newbornsin an Era of Changing Marijuana Laws</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/reporting/</guid>
      <description>i n partial fulfillment of the requirements of the Master’s in Public Health degree Tufts University School of Medicine Adviser: Marcia Boumil 2 Abstract This qualitative analysis examines the intersection of two separate sets of policy :
Mandated reporting of child abuse &amp;amp; neglect, and the state level regulation of marijuana, or cannabis. Through policies and laws created to address the needs of infants who are born
exposed to controlled substances, substance exposed newborn (SEN) initiatives provide the focal point at which these two regimes come together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marijuana and Child Custody</title>
      <link>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/custody/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flca.netlify.com/writing/custody/</guid>
      <description>Originally published in Mass Grass.
One of the most common types of cases heard in family court — and one of the most bitterly fought — is child custody. Spend a single day in one court room at any courthouse in Massachusetts or elsewhere in the country and you’ll hear a whole host of allegations made by parents or their legal representatives about each other. Often these accusations have to do with cannabis for medicinal or recreational use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>